Contact

5808 Spring Hill Dr McKinney TX 75070 314-380-4277 (Mobile) leo_carter_jr@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/leo-carter-r-n-748a7b93 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Case Management
Clinical Research
Account Management

LEO CARTER, R.N.

RN Case Manager at Methodist McKinney Hospital Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

R.N., CASE/CARE MANAGEMENT, CLINICAL PERFORMANCE, ACCOUNT MANAGEMENT

Registered Nurse with twenty plus years of experience in healthcare. Proficient in delivering age, gender, and culturally appropriate health care. Team oriented work ethic, with a great desire and potential for leadership. Experience in contract/pricing negotiation, product attribution and distribution, physician relations, patient assessment/ treatment plans/outcomes. A strong advocate of technological advances and cost reduction in health care. Great collaboration with pharmacy and laboratory areas. Served on a Service Excellence committee to raise healthcare delivery standards throughout an organization. Extensive customer service experience.

Experience

Methodist McKinney Hospital RN Case Manager December 2018 - Present (1 year 8 months) McKinney, TX

Baylor Scott & White Health
RN Care Coordinator
March 2015 - December 2018 (3 years 10 months)

VHA Inc.

2 years 4 months

Performance Improvement Program Manager June 2014 - February 2015 (9 months) Irving, TX

Collaborated with the Center of Medicare & Medicaid Services, John Hopkins Hospital's Armstrong Institute for Patient Safety and Quality, and nearly 200 VHA Hospital Engagement Network (HEN) hospitals and systems, towards

reducing hospital acquired conditions as required by the Affordable Care Act of 2010.

- Researched thousands of databases and built resource and reference packets for quick review for member and non-member health care organizations (HCOs).
- Maintained a web page co-sponsored by the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), as well as maintained a listserve for member healthcare organizations and a project database for company team members.

Member Service Specialist/Account Manager November 2012 - June 2014 (1 year 8 months) Irving, TX

- Managed accounts for over a dozen hospital systems in New England.
- First contact for member concerns/requests.
- Implemented strategies that ensured financial and operational improvements, including price discrepancy resolution, standardization performance monitoring and development of quarterly business reviews.
- Communication with suppliers on member issues as well as collaborating with suppliers on new initiatives and offerings.

aptitude LLC Nurse Consultant May 2012 - November 2012 (7 months) Irving, TX

Consultation involving product placement in correct categories in relation to creating streamline catalogs for material management in hospital organizations, with a strong focus in cardiology and surgical products.

UT Southwestern Medical Center
Heart and Lung Transplant Step-down ICU RN
June 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 6 months)
Dallas, TX

Provided adult care for heart and bilateral lung transplant patients perioperatively.

- Experienced with internal and external pacemakers, and ventricular assistive devices.
- Management of advanced cardiac IV drips, telemetry monitoring and interpretation, insertion and maintenance of IV catheters, phlebotomy and lab value interpretation.
- Responsible for patient education, medication education and administration.
 transitional care and discharge planning.

Medical Staffing Network Travel Nurse June 2008 - June 2011 (3 years 1 month)

Washington/California

- Served as an RN in several states including Washington, California, Missouri, and Texas
- Served in a wide variety of areas of practice, including, but not limited to: emergency room transitional unit, express admitting unit, ambulatory care center, medical-surgical, oncology, orthopedics, and telemetry areas.
- Management of advanced cardiac IV drips, telemetry monitoring and interpretation, insertion and maintenance of IV catheters, phlebotomy and lab value interpretation.

BJC HealthCare Heart Transplant RN December 2006 - June 2008 (1 year 7 months) St. Louis, MO

- Perioperative adult care for heart transplant patients in the heart transplant step-down unit.
- Experienced with internal and external pacemakers, and ventricular assistive devices.
- Managed advanced cardiac IV drips, telemetry monitoring and interpretation, insertion and maintenance of IV catheters, phlebotomy and lab value interpretation.
- Responsible for patient education, medication education and administration, transitional care and discharge planning,

Missouri Baptist Medical Center Certified Surgical Technologist, CNA, Rehabilitation Technician May 1990 - December 2006 (16 years 8 months) St. Louis, MO

Passed instruments and assisted general surgeons in various inpatient and outpatient surgical procedures. Assisted registered nurses and physical therapists on a neurological/renal specialty unit, cardiac, orthopedics and rehabilitation areas with direct patient care. Nurse assistant instructor and trainer.

Education

St. Louis Community College

Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse \cdot (2004 - 2006)

Harris-Stowe State University